



Jonathan Pierce

UI/UX Designer & Front-End Developer

What started as a love for visual design and applications, evolved into a blend of solving complex UX problems and delivering clean, effective, front-end experiences. My experience with multi-platform organizations has taught me the value in thinking large by applying Atomic Design principles to modern design systems.

CONTACT

Ozark, MO 417-849-3965

piercedesign22@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science 2006 - 2010 Communication Studies Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA

APPS & SKILLS

Adobe XD

Sketch

InVision

Adobe Creative Cloud

Adobe Experience Manager

Responsive Design

Application Design

iOS Design

Design Systems

Atomic Design

Agile

Google Analytics

JIRA/Confluence

Github

HTML5/Sass

Zurb Foundation

Bootstrap

Branding

EXPERIENCE

Bass Pro Shops 2019 - Current

Creative Manager in Springfield, MO

Responsible for the leadership, direction, and mentorship of a team of designers, copywriters and front-end developers. This includes leading creative and holistic thinking across diverse product releases, platforms, and devices for White River Marine Group. Also responsible for delivering a UX vision, along with a plan for evolutionary, iterative updates, that actualize the larger vision over time.

Bass Pro Shops 2015 - 2019

Senior UI/UX Designer in Springfield, MO

Responsible for the UI/UX design for White River Marine Group; the parent company for marine brands like Tracker, Ranger, Nitro, Mako, Triton, Bass Pro Boating Center and more. This role's primary focus is centered around the migration to Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) for all brand websites. Aside from the UI/UX design, this includes creating and maintaining a central design system and component library, UX design for AEM internal authors and story writing for product requirements.

Dapper Shopping, Inc. 2014 - 2015

Lead UI/UX Designer in San Francisco, CA

Responsible for the overall UI/UX of the iOS app Dapper (for men) and Moxy (for women). Other roles include brand identity design, wireframing concepts, prototyping interactions, quality assurance and testing, design and HTML/CSS of the marketing website, design and HTML for transaction emails and marketing materials for web/print media.

TRAINING & AWARDS

AAF Gold Addy

Tracker Off Road Website, 2020 Heartland

Apple App Store Feature

Moxy, April 2015 Best New Apps and Lifestyle

Dapper, November 2014
Best New Apps, Lifestyle and Buy with
Apple Pay

Reach Design Leadership Conference

2017 New York, NY

Adobe Summit

2018 Las Vegas, NV

Nielsen Norman Group

UX Training 2019 Boston, MA UX Training 2017 Chicago, IL UX Training 2012 Chicago, IL

2012 AMA Prism Award

Corporate Identity
Pickering Creative Group

Liberty University 2012 - 2014

Senior UI Designer in Lynchburg, VA

Design team lead for all web and app related projects. Responsible for creating and enforcing brand guidelines, prioritizing and assigning projects to designers and wireframing overall UX of each product. Projects included iOS and Android applications, responsive websites, complex internal web applications and student facing app tools.

Pickering Creative Group 2010 - 2012

Graphic Designer in Lynchburg, VA

Designed and developed ideas for various clients along the midwest and east coast. Included branding, web design, web development, print advertising, and marketing strategies.